<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Project Benefit</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
                Automation and simplification of information management related to the courses is the benefit of the
                University Course Listing system.
            </p>
            <p>
                A University Course Listing would be much more efficiently handled through an online system over a
                printed list, or book. No longer would you need to reprint a book of courses every so often, updating
                all the course changes made since the last update. An online system would waste no paper and therefore
                could be updated with even the smallest of changes, preventing the need to create a collection of
                changes for the next updating of a book. This system could also automatically send out e-mails informing
                everyone the changes made when there is an update. Searching for courses online would also be much
                easier with the ability to use a search feature to narrow courses down, or to find a specific course,
                rather than searching the table of contents and then flipping to the right page with a book.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Goals">
            <p>
                The goal of “Course List” project is to automate and simplify the manual process. It moves the manual
                process to an online system and sysadmin, students can work within a simple workflow based on their
                role.
            </p>
            <p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Role</th>
                        <th>Operation</th>
                        <th>Manual Process</th>
                        <th>Automated Process</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>sysadmin</td>
                        <td>Looking for a course</td>
                        <td>Open a drawer and find the printed list.</td>
                        <td>Login, open list. Probably input some search criterion.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>sysadmin</td>
                        <td>Create/Edit/Delete courses</td>
                        <td>
                            Print another 1000 copy of new course list and email/call every student that the course is
                            changed. Please com and get new version of the it.
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            Commit the change online. Everybody can see the latest version there. It can even send
                            emails to the possible related student automatically.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>student</td>
                        <td>Register/drop a course</td>
                        <td>
                            Call sysadmin that I want to register a course. Probably he will refuse because the
                            prerequisite courses are not taken.
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            Check the courses and push “Register” button. If prerequisite is not satisfied, the course
                            will not be checkable.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="The Roadmap">
            <p>
                After the student management modules are done, it will be convenient for students to add/drop courses
                online instead of repeated telephone calls and manual paperwork. The process for student to get
                transcript, pay tuition, view his status will be further automated and simplified.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>