<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Course List Overview</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Project Introduction">
            <p>
                The collegiate world demands a reliable, easy method that allows students and administrators alike to
                control college courses. The “CourseList” project aims to do exactly this. Software allows this
                otherwise messy task to be automated and simplified.
            </p>
            <p>
                CourseList will be accessible both by students and by administrators. Each type of user has his/her own
                set of capabilities. Students will be able to search through courses, looking up course descriptions,
                and adding or dropping classes. Administrators will have the ability to create, edit, or delete courses,
                as well as gather information regarding their students. Specifically, CourseList breaks down into the
                following modules:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Course Management (by sysadmin)
                        <ul>
                            <li>List, search, delete, or create courses</li>
                            <li>Change existing course</li>
                            <li>Set course prerequisites/co-requisites</li>
                            <li>Manage the teachers in system</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Teacher workbench (by teacher)
                        <ul>
                            <li>Show my courses</li>
                            <li>Manage the students in my courses</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Student Workbench (by student)
                        <ul>
                            <li>Show the courses that I'm currently taking</li>
                            <li>Show a transcript including all related courses</li>
                            <li>
                                Register or drop a course (based on course dependency; the student may not be able to
                                see all available courses for him to register)
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>
                As the project develops, additional features may be added, such as transcript requests, degree audits,
                or contact capabilities.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Be Attention">
            <p>
                Courselist is a pure academic project only for study purpose. It's not intent to solve any real industry
                problem or become a software product. Currently it's under
                <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/cddl1.php">CDDL-1.0</a>
                license.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>