<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Install and run</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="For administrators">
            <p>
                In this scenario, the administrator will log in and create a new course to be posted on the course board
                and assign an existing teacher to teach that course.
            </p>
            <p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Action</th>
                        <th>Result</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log In as administrator</td>
                        <td>
                            <p>
                                Administrator sees the home menu under System Navigation which includes the “Course
                                Listing” Tab, the “My Information” tab and “Waterview Overview” tab.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                Administrator also sees the list of current users that are able to log in to the system
                                as an administrator, teacher, or student.
                            </p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Course Listing icon to add a course to the course board</td>
                        <td>
                            Course Management, Teacher Workbench, and Student Workbench tabs pop up under course listing
                            tab.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Course Management icon</td>
                        <td>Course board, Create course, and teacher tabs pop up under Course Management tab.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Create Course</td>
                        <td>
                            The main page will ask the administrator for the course prefix, title, description,
                            co-requisite, and course number.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>After filling out the fields, click on create course</td>
                        <td>The main page will immediately show the updated course board with the new added course.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on course code to assign teacher</td>
                        <td>The Edit course page will be displayed detailing the entire course.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Use the drop down box to select the teacher, and press save changes</td>
                        <td>
                            The main screen will show the updated course board with the teacher assigned to that
                            specific course.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log out of the System</td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="For teachers">
            <p>In this scenario John Goodman, a teacher will assign a student to one of his classes.</p>
            <p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Action</th>
                        <th>Result</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log in as John Goodman (using john user name and password)</td>
                        <td>
                            <p>
                                System Navigation menu will show Home directory and the subdirectories of Course
                                Listing, My Information, and Waterview Overview.
                            </p>
                            <p>Also the main page will show the current list of users</p>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Course Listing icon</td>
                        <td>
                            Course Management and Teacher Workbench directories will show up under Course Listing
                            directory.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Teacher workbench icon</td>
                        <td>My course sub directory will appear</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on &quot;My courses&quot; subdirectory</td>
                        <td>A list of the classes that John Goodman will appear on the main page.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on one of the course codes to add a student to that class</td>
                        <td>
                            A detailed description will be shown on the main page, as well as a section that allows the
                            teacher to add or remove a student from that class.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            Use the drop down menu to choose a student to assign to that class and click on add student
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            The New student will be shown on the list of students for that class with a default grade of
                            F.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log Off as John Goodman.</td>
                        <td />
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="For students">
            <p>In this scenario the Tim Allen, a student, is going to drop on of his classes.</p>
            <p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Action</th>
                        <th>Result</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log in as Tim Allen(use tim as user name and password)</td>
                        <td>
                            System navigation menu will display Home directory and the subdirectories of Course Listing,
                            My Information and Waterview Overview.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Course Listing sub directory icon</td>
                        <td>
                            Course Mangement and Student workbench subdirectories will appear under Course listing
                            directory.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on Student workbench icon</td>
                        <td>My courses and Transript directories will appear</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on My courses</td>
                        <td>Displays all current courses that Tim Allen is taking</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Click on one of the check boxes of a certain class and click on drop selected button.</td>
                        <td>The main page will refresh and show that Tim is not taking that class any more.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Log off.</td>
                        <td></td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>