<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>What we have</title>
        <author email="chinajoeblack@hotmail.com">Jiaqi Guo</author>
    </properties>
    <head>
        <script type="text/javascript" src="js/head.js" />
    </head>
    <body>
        <section name="Hosted projects">
            <p>
                This is a full list of projects founded and hosted in Cyclops Group. Not all of these projects are under
                active development. Please follow the link to find out the detail of each project.
            </p>
            <p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Name</th>
                        <th>Description</th>
                        <th>Status</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/waterview">waterview</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>Componentized web application framework based on Plexus, commons-jelly and Velocity.</td>
                        <td>2.0 release is scheduled</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/tornado">tornado</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>Tornado is a web application framework, an enriched servlet of Apache Jakarta Turbine.</td>
                        <td>First version is released</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/levistone">levistone</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>A database access interface higher than JDBC. Very similar to Apache Torque.</td>
                        <td>I think it is dead. JDO could be a much better solution that it.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/amulets">amulets</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>Amulets are a set of maven plugins for the development of other projects.</td>
                        <td>Two plugins are released. Several other plugins are still in planning.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/laputa">laputa</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>Laputa is expected to be a collaboration platform based on waterview and tornado</td>
                        <td>Planning</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://www.cyclopsgroup.com">shopwindow</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>The project is this website itself.</td>
                        <td>Stable</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>nimbus</td>
                        <td>The portal website for the next generation of cyclopsgroup website</td>
                        <td>Planning</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/courselist">courselist</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>A simple academic web application which maintains a list of college courses.</td>
                        <td>Under development</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/jmainboard">jmainboard</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            A light weight plugable components framework. Additional module can be easily developed and
                            plug into this framework.
                            <font color="red">This project is deprecated.</font>
                        </td>
                        <td>Deprecated</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/jrepo">jrepo</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            The goal of jrepo is creating a JAVA standard for Content Management System(CMS), and
                            providing different implementation for it like file system implementation and database
                            implementation. Also, jrepo will provide applications based on this standard which provides
                            web based user interface.
                        </td>
                        <td>Planning</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="projects/jlone">jlone</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>
                            Jlone will be a CMS based web application similar to ZOPE. It will try to work with JSR 170.
                        </td>
                        <td>Planning</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://albumbuilder.sourceforge.net">albumbuilder</a>
                        </td>
                        <td>A tool to generate static photo album web site from folders of images.</td>
                        <td>Deprecated</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
