<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>What is jrepo</title>
        <author email="chinajoeblack@hotmail.com">Jiaqi Guo</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="What is jrepo">
            <p>jrepo is not a single product, application or server. It's a set of packages which include a framework of content management system, several implementation of it like file system implementation and database implementation, and presentation application for web users.</p>
            <p>The goal of jrepo projects is providing a content management system solution which is separated into API for pure Java applications and application for presentation by a proposed jrepo standard.</p>
            <p>Here's a list of jrepo projects</p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Project</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Status</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>jrepo</td>
                    <td>jrepo content management system standard API. A package of interfaces and some basic implementations.</td>
                    <td>Under development</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>jrepository</td>
                    <td>File system implementation of jrepo standard. It store contents with file system folders and files in XML.</td>
                    <td>Under development</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>torquerepo</td>
                    <td>Database implementation powered Apache Torque project.</td>
                    <td>Just an idea</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>jdorepo</td>
                    <td>JDO implmentaton of jrepo standard. It could be hard since most of JDO implementations are not mature enough. At this moment, torquerepo could be more pratical.</td>
                    <td>Just an idea</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>webrepo</td>
                    <td>Web application to present jrepo system. The application won't be a fancy web application. Instead, it'll just simply provide the ability to use a jrepo system on web. Further polish will be implemented by a portal system which is another project only exists in my mind.</td>
                    <td>Designing</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
