<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Waterview Project</title>
        <author email="jiaqi.guo@gmail.com">Jiaqi Guo</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
                Waterview is another java web application framework with a portal-system-like design. The goal of
                waterview project is to simply the development process of a web based java application. On top of an
                <a href="http://excalibur.apache.org/">Apache Avalon</a>
                compliant SOA architecture, waterview solves the common problems that a web application generally faces.
                For example, page composition, form validation, table/tree display, internationalization and page flow
                contorl. Therefore before a system is built based on waterview, 80% work is already done by the
                framework and developers will be free to focus on business logic only.
            </p>
            <p>
                The page composition in waterview is very flexible. It's very likely that waterview can be evolved to be
                a portal but now it's targeted as a web framework instead of an applicaton. Cyclopsgroup
                <a href="http://www.cyclopsgroup.com/projects/tornado">tornado</a>
                project is a portal application based on waterview.
            </p>
            I would like to delete waterview directory from my CVS server if summit project is under active development
            today. Actaully several small projects in my list used to be based on summit. However, we can not even find
            this project any longer now.
            <p>
                Waterview is under active development now. Any suggestion is welcom. Please feel free to
                <a href="mailto:jiaqi.guo@gmail.com">shoot me email</a>
                to share your idea.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Why should I be interested">
            <p>
                <b>Easy to use.</b>
                Waterview doesn't require the developers to know much to work with it. For example, only two java
                packages are exposed for normal usage. Stuff like form, table and portal are all invisible to
                developer.Please look at "Get Started" section to find out how to use it.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Simple design.</b>
                The design of waterview is unique, clean, smart and simple.
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Excellent people.</b>
                People in Cyclopsgroup foundation are all academic maniac. Many of them are PH.D. from U.S and China.
                You may find many interesting ideas and phylosophies here.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="More Documentation">
            <p>
                Many thanks to the support from
                <a href="http://www.atlassian.com">atlassian</a>
                , who offers great knowledge sharing tool, confluence to open source developers. More documentation can
                be found in
                <a href="http://www.cyclopsgroup.com/kb/display/waterview">waterview knownledge base</a>
                .
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
