<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Feature table</title>
        <author email="jiaqi.guo@gmail.com">Jiaqi Guo</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Why not Struts?">
            <p>
                This could be the first question coming to people's mind when another web application framework
                presents. Struts is the most popular option as a java web application framework today. However, the
                popular solution may not be the best solution in many cases while the solution that solves the the
                particular problem is. It's just like big company may not give you the dream job.
            </p>
            <p>
                It's hard to summarize the difference between waterview and struts in one word. Please take a look at
                the design of waterview to fi decentlygure out the difference. Generally speaking, struts is a simple
                MVC framework implementation which focus on the page flow. The other fuctions are provided by a simple
                plugin architect. In a web application, the commons problems are much more than these.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Waterview vs. Turbine">
            <p>
                The design of waterview is very similar to
                <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/turbine">turbine</a>
                while the underneath implementation makes huge difference. Both turbine and waterview is introducing a
                pluggable web application but waterview makes the way of configuring pipeline valves, error handler,
                page renderers and other components (services in turbine) unified and generic. In waterview, all these
                elements are components defined in xml file for plexus container.
            </p>
            <p>
                Basically the intention of waterview is to make turbine more componentized and unified, eliminate the
                pipeline specific definition (pipeline xml), turbine specific configuration
                (TurbineResources.properties) and introduce avalon.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Waterview vs. Summit">
            <p>Well, one difference is waterview is called waterview and summit is called summit.</p>
            <p>
                Plexus summit component is a web application with excellent design. Unfortunately it has been suffocated
                for many years because lack of development. Many ideas in waterview were initiated from summit actually.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Feature Comparison">
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Function\Project</th>
                    <th>Waterview</th>
                    <th>Struts</th>
                    <th>Turbine</th>
                    <th>Tapestry</th>
                    <th>Spingframework UI</th>
                    <th>Summit</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>Page flow</th>
                    <td>Loose</td>
                    <td>Strict and central</td>
                    <td>Loose</td>
                    <td>Loose</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>Loose</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>SOA/IOC container</th>
                    <td>Avalon, Plexus</td>
                    <td>No, plugin doesn't count</td>
                    <td>Fulcrum, Avalon</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>Springframework</td>
                    <td>Plexus</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>XML GUI Components</th>
                    <td>Supported as default</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                    <td>Supoprted</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>Velocity GUI</th>
                    <td>Supported</td>
                    <td>Supported</td>
                    <td>Supported as default</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>Supported</td>
                    <td>Supported as default</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>Form and validation</th>
                    <td>Supported loosely</td>
                    <td>Supported centrally</td>
                    <td>Supported centrally</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <th>Table, pagination</th>
                    <td>Supoprted</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>--</td>
                    <td>No</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>